so now that we have seen how the btb and
the BHT work together let's do a btb and
BHT quiz on that suppose we have the
following program this is the address of
the instruction this is the instruction
itself and these are the labels for
branches so what this program is doing
is it's moving 100 into R2 it's moving
zero into R1 and then as long as R1 and
R2 are different it's going to continue
here once R1 and R2 are the same it's
going to jump to the done label and exit
this Loop in the loop it's adding R1 to
R3 to form R4 uses that to load a value
from that address and then adds that R4
to R5 adds one to R1 and then
unconditionally branches back to this
Loop so this is the loop this is where
we exit from the loop and this is the
sort of initialization for the loop
suppose that we have a branch history
table that has only 16 entries and makes
perfect predictions about branches
suppose we also have a btb with four
entries also makes perfect predictions
and as you can see all instructions are
four bytes in size and we know that so
the question for you is how many times
do we access the BHT for each
instruction right here how many times we
access the BHT
with this address because we are
fetching this
instruction here how many times we
access the BHD with this address because
we're fetching this instruction and so
on there are eight instructions here for
each one of them we need to say how many
times we access the BHD